<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="2.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-04-26T10:28:36+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title>Cocktail Insights</title><subtitle>Helping eCommerce businesses maximise social media ROI</subtitle><entry><title>The Beta Launch of CockTail Insights</title><link href="/2016/04/26/the%20launch%20blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beta Launch of CockTail Insights" /><published>2016-04-26T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-04-26T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2016/04/26/the launch blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/04/26/the%20launch%20blog/">&lt;p&gt;
	With the rapid adoption of social media marketing by many firms and entrepreneurs for brand awareness and promotion of sales during the 21st century, it came as much of a surprise upon the realization of the lack of accurate and affordable analytical solutions for businesses like ecommerce to track their social media marketing efforts all the way down to a purchase action. The absence of the ability to enable ecommerce business owners to directly link activities on social media to the activities on their web application or site gave rise to the application &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;CockTail Insights&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A research by &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.statista.com/statistics/278414/number-of-worldwide-social-network-users/&quot;&gt;statista&lt;/a&gt; stated that the total number of social media users is 2.13B with marketers and business merchants spending a combined figure of $23.68 Billion in order to reach these billions of users. However with all these developments, 60% of marketers and business owners are clueless as to the exact percentage of their sales revenue that was influenced by their time consuming and expensive operations on their social media platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Making it almost impossible for ecommerce businesses to actually make cost-effective marketing decisions with the absence of information like the platform which contributed the most click through to the web site or application, the platform which provided the most engagement amongst fans and what content they interacted most with, the exact demographic properties of fans that engage with postings and those that actually follow through to make a purchase and finally the exact revenue contribution of the campaigns run on the  various social media platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	CockTail Insights as a tool ensures ecommerce merchants are responsible for deriving the expected results, objectives and missions of their social media marketing efforts by embarking on data-backed decision-making. Cocktail insights provides all this information using data points from both the social media analytical platform and google analytics. Through the integration users can easily track the true impact of their social media marketing toils. For maximum reporting users will have to ensure their google analytics account is well setup. This includes ensuring that age and geographical data is enabled, funnels are well setup and clearly defined goals have been established.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The user experience, user interface, feature set and information presented by Cocktail Insights is as a result of extensive and continuous research on user behavior and industry expectations with a general sense of ease being the core foundation upon which the product is built on. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;
	The images below provide a complete walkthrough of how &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;CockTail Insights&lt;/a&gt; works: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/new_business_page copy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Setup New Business&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	After a successful login process you will be required to create a business, this will enable you save your social media, google analytics and shopify credentials within this “new business”. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/integrations_page_social_media.png&quot; alt=&quot;Setup Social Media Accounts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	There is the need to integrate your social media pages as highlighted above. This allows you to post to either facebook or twitter from cocktail insights. Also, you are provided with in-depth analysis about the reach, demography and interests of your fans.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/integrations_page_shopify.png&quot; alt=&quot;Setup Shopify Store&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The Shopify store is also required to be integrated to enable the tracking of the movement of fans from your social media accounts. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/integrations_page_google_analytics.png&quot; alt=&quot;Setup Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Before proceeding to either publishing or queuing your content, the google analytics account connected to your shopify store needs to be connected as well. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
	The processes of enabling these services on our secure platform are one of ease and should take you not more than a minute to activate.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;h4&gt;After integrating all these services you can now plunge into the full functionality of cockTail insights.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish_queue_settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Setup Queue Settings&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	You can publish your content immediately or queue it to be sent at a predetermined date and time. This can be achieved by clicking the Queue Settings button highlighted above.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/queue_settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Queue Settings&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This image above will be presented upon clicking the Queue settings button. On this page you can schedule the periods during the day that you want the posts to be published. After selecting the preferred times for posting, the update button above is selected to ensure the changes are permanent.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish.png&quot; alt=&quot;Publish Post&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The highlighted section is where you write the content you want published. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish_select_shopify_image.png&quot; alt=&quot;Publish Shopify Product&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	As part of writing content, you can also take products from your database by clicking the image above. This enables you select a product from your database to post on the social media pages selected as shown below.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish_tag.png&quot; alt=&quot;Add Tag to Post&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A tag is strongly recommended to enable easy categorization of posts. Examples of tags include inspirational message, products, puzzle, funny, riddle, promotion and many others. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish_select_social_media.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select Social Media Profile&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	After providing content either in the form of text, image or both, the social media pages that you want to publish the content to should be selected by clicking on the highlighted image above.  I currently have a single page connected and therefore if I had more pages then I can choose a single page or multiple pages.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish_options.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select from Multiple Publish Options&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The post is ready for publication after the content is filled and a social media page is chosen. However, there are multiple options that you can publish the content. You can decide if you want the content to be published immediately, on a scheduled date or to allow it to join the queue.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
	Finally incase you want to post a link on your blog or share a link with your friends without posting it through social media we have you covered. By leveraging on the bit.ly shortener API we have made it made possible to track those said links. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/url.png&quot; alt=&quot;Setup Trackable Url or Links&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The descriptions of the fields are as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Url:&lt;/b&gt; This is where you put the link that you want to share.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Campaign source:&lt;/b&gt; This refers to the search engines, social networks, ad campaigns, and other sources that send users to your website, web application and blog.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Campaign Medium:&lt;/b&gt; The medium can either be a referral, organic, paid search and direct search.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Campaign Name:&lt;/b&gt; A name for the campaign. This could be a promo code, product or slogan.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Campaign Term:&lt;/b&gt; This is used for paid search.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Campaign Content:&lt;/b&gt; Used for A/B testing and content-targeted ads. Use to differentiate between ads or links that point to the same URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;As part of the features offered by CockTail Insights is the ability to gain extensive insights on all posts published from the service. Merchants are provided with insights such as demography, location, devices and others. The images below are previews of how your information will be displayed to you.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/facebook_insights.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook Insights&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The image above will provide you with all your facebook insights. It will provide you with in-depth on your posts, letting you know your fans, the content your fans resonated with most as well as recommended times for you to post to increase your odds of reaching your desired audience.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blended_insights.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blended Insights&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The image above is a blend of information from various data points. You are able to compare metrics over a period as well as match some metrics and dimensions head-to-head.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The information provided from all these outlets will empower you to make well-informed marketing decisions and increase your returns in many folds. Also, you are able to streamline relevant content for your fans.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A point of view can be a dangerous luxury when substituted for insight and understanding.- Marshall McLuhan, Canadian Communications Professor
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Panin Osei Tenkorang</name></author><summary>With the rapid adoption of social media marketing by many firms and entrepreneurs for brand awareness and promotion of sales during the 21st century, it came as much of a surprise upon the realization of the lack of accurate and affordable analytical solutions for businesses like ecommerce to track their social media marketing efforts all the way down to a purchase action. The absence of the ability to enable ecommerce business owners to directly link activities on social media to the activities on their web application or site gave rise to the application CockTail Insights.</summary></entry><entry><title>Growing our betalist with BetaList</title><link href="/2016/04/08/Growing%20our%20betalist%20with%20BetaList/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Growing our betalist with BetaList" /><published>2016-04-08T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-04-08T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2016/04/08/Growing our betalist with BetaList</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/04/08/Growing%20our%20betalist%20with%20BetaList/">&lt;p&gt;
	My team and I, three young entrepreneurs from the Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (MEST), pitched our product to a panel  of  seasoned startup entrepreneurs and venture capitalist judges at a recent MEST sponsored event.  The panel of judges included Amber Fowler of EchoVC, Nik Fasting founder, CEO and CTO of Syncano and Jorn Lyseggen founder and CEO of Meltwater. We received great feedback and we were encouraged to complete the journey we had started four months prior. Our startup journey is just beginning; three ambitious and determined entrepreneurs about to set sail from the shores of Africa with a globally relevant e-commerce tool
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our company’s product &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;Cocktail Insights&lt;/a&gt;, is designed to enable businesses  (with a focus on eCommerce businesses and merchants) to measure and maximize the returns of their social media efforts. Businesses leverage on social media to engage their audience and market their services or products. Most often than not, they find it difficult to answer questions such as:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much revenue is generated by a specific post or campaign?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is the disparity between the demography of engaging audiences on the  various social Channels and actual customers making purchases?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much revenue is generated by campaigns and posts?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Which social media platform is the best performing channel?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Which audience group should be targeted with campaigns?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What type of content drives engagement and conversion?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that by providing valuable insights to the questions above, we can help eCommerce businesses and merchants  improve their social media efforts, maximize their returns and grow their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognize that building a product and launching a startup is an ongoing journey. We had to work hard and smart to produce a product that meets the ever evolving needs of innovative e-commerce businesses and merchants. We poured hours into developing, testing and modifying  our product. After six weeks of development, our MVP was ready. Cocktail Insights has joined the African armada of startups, it was poised and ready to conquer its own share of the social media analytics and attribution market.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait…there was one more thing to do. Our MVP was ready, and the next thing to do was to acquire beta testers. We created a landing page and used social media to market it organically.  We also researched on platforms we could leverage on to build our email list; we found &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://betalist.com/&quot;&gt;BetaList&lt;/a&gt;. We did not want to spend money on something that did not work, so we decided to use the free listings of BetaList just to test it and measure its impact. Cocktail Insights was &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://betalist.com/startups/cocktail-insights&quot;&gt;publish&lt;/a&gt; on BetaList on 26th March, 2016. Within 3 days we had 175 unique sessions from Betalist and 83 sign ups, that is a conversion rate of 47%.  That is impressive for a free listing. Our email list is still growing and we are preparing to launch our beta in April, 2016.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://betalist.com/startups/cocktail-insights&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/betalist.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Sample Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Our BetaList publication&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know there will always be challenges and we would just have to find a way through it all. This time, the solution to our problem was BetaList, tomorrow it would be something else. After all, “when there is a will, there is a way”. We do not know what lies ahead, but you can only know what the future holds if you march bravely into it. Join us, as we sail into the future, a lot of Cocktail Insights would be served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;We must free ourselves of the hope that the sea will ever rest. We must learn to sail in high winds.-Aristotle Onassis&quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Kissi</name></author><summary>My team and I, three young entrepreneurs from the Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (MEST), pitched our product to a panel  of  seasoned startup entrepreneurs and venture capitalist judges at a recent MEST sponsored event.  The panel of judges included Amber Fowler of EchoVC, Nik Fasting founder, CEO and CTO of Syncano and Jorn Lyseggen founder and CEO of Meltwater. We received great feedback and we were encouraged to complete the journey we had started four months prior. Our startup journey is just beginning; three ambitious and determined entrepreneurs about to set sail from the shores of Africa with a globally relevant e-commerce tool</summary></entry><entry><title>Social media pumps revenue into eCommerce</title><link href="/2016/02/03/social%20media%20and%20ecommerce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social media pumps revenue into eCommerce" /><published>2016-02-03T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-03T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2016/02/03/social media and ecommerce</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/02/03/social%20media%20and%20ecommerce/">&lt;p&gt;Research has shown that over 60% of customers make product research online before making a purchase decision. This fact is very important to note since the growth of any eCommerce business is driven by one fundamental thing &quot;traffic&quot;. In the world of eCommerce it is true to keep an eye on metrics such as conversion rate etc, but in order to start measuring all those metrics you need to pour in the traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the eCommerce industry experienced a rocket flight growth, attaining an exponential increase of 17%. The top eCommerce companies are making a monthly revenue of $600,000 approximately, with the average eCommerce company generating about $1.1 million/month in its 3rd year. Experts have estimated that eCommerce will make over $370 billion/year in revenue in 2017, $170 billion more than what it made in 2014 ($220 billion)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although eCommerce traffic is still dominated by organic search, social media had a significant part to play in the rise of the eCommerce industry. In 2014, the top 500 retailers earned about $3.3 billion from social shopping which is a 26% increase from 2013. Social media platforms have undertaken new directives like the introduction of buy buttons that has optimzed them for eCommerce marketing &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first quarters of 2014 - 2015, social media bumped up its share of eCommerce referrals to 200%. The dominating social commerce power house, Facebook, continues to show impressive social commerce statistics. Facebook accounts for over 50% of social referrals and 65% of social revenue. Pinterest is also a major social commerce contributor. It generated 16% of social revenue despite an audience of 6.5 times smaller than twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better understand how social media is contributing to the eCommerce industry, Shopify analysed 37 million social visits that led to 529,000 orders. Within the social category, Facebook dominated as a source of traffic and sales with an average of 85% of orders on Shopify coming from Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/infographics/social-commerce&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/social.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Sample Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Infographic of the contibution of various social media channels in Shopify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform that pulled a surprise was Polyvore, which generated the highest average order value. Also instagram generated higher average oders than Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest.
Facebook has the highest conversion rate of 1.85% on shopify. It is no doubt that social media plays an important role in eCommerce and contributes to the revenue generation of the industry hence, eCommerce businesses and merchants should be able  &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;measure the ROI of the scoal media efforts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt; manage social media accounts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;identify best perfoming channels&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its no doubt that the eCommerce industry has seen an impresive growth over the past 4 years. For now all the trends and statistics show that it is not slowing down anytime soon and it has its focus aimed for the stars.
One can say the recent rise of the eCommerce industry can be attributed to the increased number of tech savvy consumers, rise of smartphones, beter logistics, emerging new markets and last but not the least, social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;We dont have a choice on whether we DO social media, the question is how well we DO it&quot; - Erik Qualman&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/social-commerce-2015-report-2015-6&quot;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vemployee.com/staging_old/blog/e-commerce-statistics-that-will-blow-your-mind/&quot;&gt;v-employee&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trueship.com/blog/2015/01/06/powerful-social-media-ecommerce-statistics-that-will-make-you-rethink-e-retailing-altogether/&quot;&gt;Trueship&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/infographics/social-commerce&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Kissi</name></author><summary>Research has shown that over 60% of customers make product research online before making a purchase decision. This fact is very important to note since the growth of any eCommerce business is driven by one fundamental thing &quot;traffic&quot;. In the world of eCommerce it is true to keep an eye on metrics such as conversion rate etc, but in order to start measuring all those metrics you need to pour in the traffic.</summary></entry></feed>
