<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="2.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-04-10T21:55:01+00:00</updated><id>http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/</id><title>Cocktail Insights</title><subtitle>Helping eCommerce businesses maximise social media ROI</subtitle><entry><title>Growing our betalist with BetaList</title><link href="http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/2016/04/08/Growing%20our%20betalist%20with%20BetaList/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Growing our betalist with BetaList" /><published>2016-04-08T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-04-08T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/2016/04/08/Growing our betalist with BetaList</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/2016/04/08/Growing%20our%20betalist%20with%20BetaList/">&lt;p&gt;
My team and I, three young entrepreneurs from the Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (MEST), pitched our product to a panel  of  seasoned startup entrepreneurs and venture capitalist judges at a recent MEST sponsored event.  The panel of judges included Amber Fowler of EchoVC, Nik Fasting founder, CEO and CTO of Syncano and Jorn Lyseggen founder and CEO of Meltwater. We received great feedback and we were encouraged to complete the journey we had started four months prior. Our startup journey is just beginning; three ambitious and determined entrepreneurs about to set sail from the shores of Africa with a globally relevant e-commerce tool
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our company’s product &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;Cocktail Insights&lt;/a&gt;, is designed to enable businesses  (with a focus on eCommerce businesses and merchants) to measure and maximize the returns of their social media efforts. Businesses leverage on social media to engage their audience and market their services or products. Most often than not, they find it difficult to answer questions such as:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much revenue is generated by a specific post or campaign?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is the disparity between the demography of engaging audiences on the  various social Channels and actual customers making purchases?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much revenue is generated by campaigns and posts?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Which social media platform is the best performing channel?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Which audience group should be targeted with campaigns?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What type of content drives engagement and conversion?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that by providing valuable insights to the questions above, we can help eCommerce businesses and merchants  improve their social media efforts, maximize their returns and grow their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognize that building a product and launching a startup is an ongoing journey. We had to work hard and smart to produce a product that meets the ever evolving needs of innovative e-commerce businesses and merchants. We poured hours into developing, testing and modifying  our product. After six weeks of development, our MVP was ready. Cocktail Insights has joined the African armada of startups, it was poised and ready to conquer its own share of the social media analytics and attribution market.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait…there was one more thing to do. Our MVP was ready, and the next thing to do was to acquire beta testers. We created a landing page and used social media to market it organically.  We also researched on platforms we could leverage on to build our email list; we found &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://betalist.com/&quot;&gt;BetaList&lt;/a&gt;. We did not want to spend money on something that did not work, so we decided to use the free listings of BetaList just to test it and measure its impact. Cocktail Insights was &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://betalist.com/startups/cocktail-insights&quot;&gt;publish&lt;/a&gt; on BetaList on 26th March, 2016. Within 3 days we had 175 unique sessions from Betalist and 83 sign ups, that is a conversion rate of 47%.  That is impressive for a free listing. Our email list is still growing and we are preparing to launch our beta in April, 2016.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know there will always be challenges and we would just have to find a way through it all. This time, the solution to our problem was BetaList, tomorrow it would be something else. After all, “when there is a will, there is a way”. We do not know what lies ahead, but you can only know what the future holds if you march bravely into it. Join us, as we sail into the future, a lot of Cocktail Insights would be served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;We must free ourselves of the hope that the sea will ever rest. We must learn to sail in high winds.-Aristotle Onassis&quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Kissi</name></author><summary>My team and I, three young entrepreneurs from the Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (MEST), pitched our product to a panel  of  seasoned startup entrepreneurs and venture capitalist judges at a recent MEST sponsored event.  The panel of judges included Amber Fowler of EchoVC, Nik Fasting founder, CEO and CTO of Syncano and Jorn Lyseggen founder and CEO of Meltwater. We received great feedback and we were encouraged to complete the journey we had started four months prior. Our startup journey is just beginning; three ambitious and determined entrepreneurs about to set sail from the shores of Africa with a globally relevant e-commerce tool</summary></entry><entry><title>Social media pumps revenue into eCommerce</title><link href="http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/2016/02/03/social%20media%20and%20ecommerce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social media pumps revenue into eCommerce" /><published>2016-02-03T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-03T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/2016/02/03/social media and ecommerce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/2016/02/03/social%20media%20and%20ecommerce/">&lt;p&gt;Research has shown that over 60% of customers make product research online before making a purchase decision. This fact is very important to note since the growth of any eCommerce business is driven by one fundamental thing &quot;traffic&quot;. In the world of eCommerce it is true to keep an eye on metrics such as conversion rate etc, but in order to start measuring all those metrics you need to pour in the traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the eCommerce industry experienced a rocket flight growth, attaining an exponential increase of 17%. The top eCommerce companies are making a monthly revenue of $600,000 approximately, with the average eCommerce company generating about $1.1 million/month in its 3rd year. Experts have estimated that eCommerce will make over $370 billion/year in revenue in 2017, $170 billion more than what it made in 2014 ($220 billion)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although eCommerce traffic is still dominated by organic search, social media had a significant part to play in the rise of the eCommerce industry. In 2014, the top 500 retailers earned about $3.3 billion from social shopping which is a 26% increase from 2013. Social media platforms have undertaken new directives like the introduction of buy buttons that has optimzed them for eCommerce marketing &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first quarters of 2014 - 2015, social media bumped up its share of eCommerce referrals to 200%. The dominating social commerce power house, Facebook, continues to show impressive social commerce statistics. Facebook accounts for over 50% of social referrals and 65% of social revenue. Pinterest is also a major social commerce contributor. It generated 16% of social revenue despite an audience of 6.5 times smaller than twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better understand how social media is contributing to the eCommerce industry, Shopify analysed 37 million social visits that led to 529,000 orders. Within the social category, Facebook dominated as a source of traffic and sales with an average of 85% of orders on Shopify coming from Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/infographics/social-commerce&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.cocktailinsights.com/img/social.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Sample Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Infographic of the contibution of various social media channels in Shopify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform that pulled a surprise was Polyvore, which generated the highest average order value. Also instagram generated higher average oders than Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest.
Facebook has the highest conversion rate of 1.85% on shopify. It is no doubt that social media plays an important role in eCommerce and contributes to the revenue generation of the industry hence, eCommerce businesses and merchants should be able  &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;measure the ROI of the scoal media efforts&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt; manage social media accounts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cocktailinsights.com/&quot;&gt;identify best perfoming channels&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reaching for the Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its no doubt that the eCommerce industry has seen an impresive growth over the past 4 years. For now all the trends and statistics show that it is not slowing down anytime soon and it has its focus aimed for the stars.
One can say the recent rise of the eCommerce industry can be attributed to the increased number of tech savvy consumers, rise of smartphones, beter logistics, emerging new markets and last but not the least, social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;We dont have a choice on whether we DO social media, the question is how well we DO it&quot; - Erik Qualman&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/social-commerce-2015-report-2015-6&quot;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vemployee.com/staging_old/blog/e-commerce-statistics-that-will-blow-your-mind/&quot;&gt;v-employee&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trueship.com/blog/2015/01/06/powerful-social-media-ecommerce-statistics-that-will-make-you-rethink-e-retailing-altogether/&quot;&gt;Trueship&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/infographics/social-commerce&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Kissi</name></author><summary>Research has shown that over 60% of customers make product research online before making a purchase decision. This fact is very important to note since the growth of any eCommerce business is driven by one fundamental thing &quot;traffic&quot;. In the world of eCommerce it is true to keep an eye on metrics such as conversion rate etc, but in order to start measuring all those metrics you need to pour in the traffic.</summary></entry></feed>
